<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>/</title>
   
   <link>/</link>
   <description>Thoughts on Big Data Analytics, Machine Learning, and Product Development</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   
   <title>
   <![CDATA[ Valens DataLabs Blog ]]>
   </title>
   <description>
   <![CDATA[ Thoughts on Big Data Analytics, Machine Learning, and Product Development ]]>
   </description>
   <link>/</link>
   <image>
   <url>/assets/images/favicon.png</url>
   <title>Valens DataLabs Blog</title>
   <link>/</link>
   </image>
   <generator>Jekyll 3.6.2</generator>
   <lastBuildDate></lastBuildDate>
   <atom:link href="/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
   <ttl>60</ttl>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Introducing Our New Logo!</title>
	  <link>/introducing-our-new-logo</link>
		
				
		
				
						<author>Pranav Shukla</author>
				
		
	  <pubDate>2020-02-20T17:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/introducing-our-new-logo</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>We are proud to announce the launch of the new company logo as part of the ongoing evolution of our company’s brand.</p>

<p>Our business has grown and evolved over the years, and we felt it was time for a change. We have refreshed our logo to reflect who we are today and to symbolise our future.</p>

<p><img src="assets/images/posts/valens_datalabs_blue.png" /></p>

<p>After careful consideration, we chose a new logo that reflects a more modern and minimalist design. The letters VDL for Valens DataLabs have been creatively encoded within the logo. The overarching circle represents our spirit of striving for excellence in everything we do.</p>

<p>In our effort to respect diversity, we are not limiting ourselves to one colour for the logo.</p>

<p>We have put a lot of work into finding the design that will represent us in the years to come and we hope you like it.</p>

<hr />

<p>In the upcoming days, we will be updating all our collaterals, business cards, etc with the new logo. We realise that changing a logo is a process that can involve many steps and take some time, so we will finalise it gradually.</p>

<p>If you have used the Valens DataLabs logo in any of your marketing materials, please assist us in updating them. We appreciate your kind support. If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to contact us.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
